Guide to the Kenneth Pitzer Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Kenneth Pitzer papers
1968-1980
1968-1970
SC0087
Pitzer, Kenneth S., (Kenneth Sanborn), 1914-1997
4 Linear feet
Papers include correspondence, press releases and articles relating to Dr. Pitzer's appointment to and resignation from the presidency of Stanford; his chron files; subject files; and appointment book (Aug. 1969-Aug. 1970).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Kenneth Pitzer, 1970, and Bancroft Library, 1998.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Sixth president of Stanford University, December 1968 to September 1, 1970.
Description of the Collection
Papers include correspondence, press releases and articles relating to Dr. Pitzer's appointment to and resignation from the presidency of Stanford; his chron files; subject files; and appointment book (Aug. 1969-Aug. 1970).
Access Terms
Pitzer, Kenneth S., (Kenneth Sanborn), 1914-1997; Universities and colleges--Administration.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Series 1
  - Correspondence re resignation, A – K (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence re resignation, L – Z (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Trustees (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Press releases, news articles (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1998-074
  - Correspondence A - K Pitzer resignation from Stanford (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence L - Z Pitzer resignation from Stanford (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Trustees Pitzer resignation from Stanford (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stanford, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Stanford, later items to 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Stanford trip - August 26-28, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stanford trip - Sept. 9-12, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stanford appointment (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Architecture at Stanford (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brandin, Alf E. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Candidates (misc.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clippings 1968 Aug. - Sept. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Glaser, Robert J. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Stanford trip, Sept. 18-21, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Trustees, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cuthbertson, Kenneth, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Re students or student matters, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Discussion with Stanford students (Sept. 1968) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Daily (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chemistry Dept - Stanford (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Law School (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stanford - Library (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cleaver case (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Stanford - H&S budget (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Stanford - Humanities & Sciences (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - KSP acknowledgements re Stanford appointment - first half of alphabet (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - KSP acknowledgements re Stanford appointment - second half of alphabet (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Re Stanford appointment - no reply (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Acknowledge of appointment from Stanford people (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hoover Institute (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Academic Council, 1968-69 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Academic Council, 1969-70 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Senate, 1968-69 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Senate, 1969-70 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Appointment and Tenure Policy (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - AAUP - governance of University (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Executive Organization & Personnel Advisory Committee (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - University Advisory Committee (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - B.Y.U. issue (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Research Institute (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Resignation clippings, etc., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Press releases, news articles Pitzer resignation from Stanford (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Stanford misc. financial information (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Stanford University misc. 1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Pitzer's Chronological file Stanford material, Aug. - Nov. 1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Reading file, December 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Reading file, January 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Reading file, February 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Reading file, March 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Reading file, April 1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Reading file, May 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Reading file, June 1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Reading file, July 1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Reading file, August 1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Reading file, September 1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Reading file, October 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Reading file, November 1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Reading file, December 1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Reading file, January 1970 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Reading file, February 1970 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Reading file, March 1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Reading file, April 1970 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Reading file, May 1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Reading file, June 1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Reading file, July 1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Reading file, Sept. 1970 - June 1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Appointment book, Aug. 1969 - Aug. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)